Mss.Rec.81 Mss.Rec.81
American Philosophical Society
- Audio recordings
  - Corn Silk and Two Faces Mythology [1 of 2], 1969; 09-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:32; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
  - The Foolish One, 1969; 09-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:37; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
  - Hidatsa story about a young woman and some puppies, 1969; 09-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:40; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Anthropological linguistics; Dogs--Folklore; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Mandan Indians--Folklore
  - Hidatsa story about a porcupine, 1969; 09-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:40; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Mandan Indians--Folklore; Porcupines--Folklore
  - Word list from Matthews English to Hidatsa, 1969; 09-08; 1.0 .mp3; 01:03:16; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians; Hidatsa language
  - Corn Silk and Two Faces [2 of 2], 1969; 09-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:25; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
  - Shell Robe Bundle History [1 of 2], 1969; 09-10; 1.0 .mp3; 01:28:49; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
    Collector's documentation indicates that a Mandan-English version of this story was given by Otter Sage, but this version cannot be found on the tape transferred from the collector's master tape.
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Hidatsa Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Mandan Indians--Folklore; Mandan Indians--Rites and ceremonies
  - Shell Robe Bundle History [2 of 2], 1969; 09-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:35:40; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
  - Corn Bundle Myths, 1969; 09-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:58:22; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
  - First Creator and Elk Head [1 of 2], 1969; 09-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:42; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
    Anthropological linguistics; Creation--Mythology; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Hidatsa mythology; Mandan Indians--Folklore
  - First Creator and Elk Head [2 of 2], 1969; 10-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:25:34; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
  - First Creator and the Children, 1969; 10-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:32:16; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
  - Marriages in Area Little Missouri to Red Buttes, 1969; 10-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:45:58; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Predominantly in English, with some miscellaneous terms in Hidatsa and Mandan.
  - Marriages by Reservation Districts, 1969; 10-04; 1.0 .mp3; 01:48:24; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
  - Completes Marriages by Reservation Districts, 1969; 10-05; 1.0 .mp3; 01:03:27; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
  - Crows Heart's trading post and family economy after General Allotment established, 1969; 10-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:44:49; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
  - First Creator and the Mother-in-law, 1969; 10-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:02; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
  - First Creator and his Daughter, 1969; 10-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:17:35; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
  - First Creator and Fat, 1969; 10-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:34:53; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
  - First Creator and the Mountain Lion, 1969; 10-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:39:57; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
  - Origin of Horse and Horse Ceremonies, 1969; 11-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:46:48; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Horses
  - The Woman and Hot Food, 1969; 11-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:09; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore
  - Myth of the Bear (completed), 1969; 11-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:09; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
    Anthropological linguistics; Bears--Folklore; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Mandan Indians--Folklore
  - Village Conflict of Crow Flies High Band, 1969; 11-04; 1.0 .mp3; 01:01:42; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--History; Indians of North America--North Dakota--History; Mandan Indians--History
  - First Creator and Boys with a Robe (Part I), 1969; 11-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:33:35; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Hidatsa mythology; Mandan Indians--Folklore; Mandan language
  - Complete First Creator and Boys with a Robe, 1969; 11-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:26:34; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
  - Miscellaneous short stories, 1969; 11-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:11; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
    Listed in table of contents as "Miscellaneous Short Stories" but contains only one story. Story concerns a woman and child, the child's transformation into a bird, and the woman's transformation into a butte. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Arapahoan language of the same name.
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Mandan Indians--Folklore; Mother and child--Folklore
  - Packs Antelope Myth, 1969; 11-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:58:34; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Folklore; Indians of North America--North Dakota--History
  - Completes Packs Antelope Myth, 1969; 11-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:33:56; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
  - Conversation on relatives and Crow Flies High, 1969; 11-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:49; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--History; Hidatsa Indians--Social life and customs; Indians of North America--North Dakota--History; Mandan Indians--Social life and customs
  - The Village of Women Only, 1969; 11-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:21:46; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
  - Mandan and Hidatsa translations, 1969; 11-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:36; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
    English given by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by Hidatsa translation by Annie Crows Heart Eagle and Mandan translation by Otter Sage. The material is most likely from Crows Heart Autobiography. This material was found on the end of tape 66 after completion of final item listed on the accompanying table of contents. Collector's note indicates that other material from a master tape was previously recorded on this tape. This program is the remaining portion that was not recorded over.
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians; Hidatsa language; Mandan Indians; Mandan language
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-07-23; 12-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:56:50; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
    The autobiographical text was collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Crows Heart, a Mandan, in 1947. The recording consists of the English version of the text being read in short chunks by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by free translations into Mandan, then Hidatsa, by Crows Heart's daughter, Annie Crows Heart Eagle. Begins at page 86 of original text. At 01:45:13 recording unaccountably jumps to different recording session with Alfred Bowers giving English, Otter Sage giving Mandan, and Annie Crows Heart Eagle giving Hidatsa. Content most likely also from Crows Heart Autobiography. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name.
    Anthropological linguistics; Autobiography; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--History; Mandan Indians--Biography; Mandan Indians--History
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-07; 12-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:39:18; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    The autobiographical text was collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Crows Heart, a Mandan, in 1947. The recording consists of the English version of the text being read in short chunks by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by free translations into Mandan, then Hidatsa, by Crows Heart's daughter, Annie Crows Heart Eagle. Begins at page 94 of original text. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name.
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-07; 12-03; 1.0 .mp3; 01:43:04; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    The autobiographical text was collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Crows Heart, a Mandan, in 1947. The recording consists of the English version of the text being read in short chunks by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by free translations into Mandan, then Hidatsa, by Crows Heart's daughter, Annie Crows Heart Eagle. Begins at page 99 of original text. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name.
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-07; 12-04; 1.0 .mp3; 01:39:38; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
    The autobiographical text was collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Crows Heart, a Mandan, in 1947. The recording consists of the English version of the text being read in short chunks by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by free translations into Mandan, then Hidatsa, by Crows Heart's daughter, Annie Crows Heart Eagle. From 35:40 to end, translation into Mandan taken over by Otter Sage. During much of this section, Annie Crows Heart Eagle's speech becomes difficult to hear due to low recording levels. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name.
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-07; 12-05; 1.0 .mp3; 01:07:47; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    The autobiographical text was collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Crows Heart, a Mandan, in 1947. The recording consists of the English version of the text being read in short chunks by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by free translations into Mandan, then Hidatsa, by Crows Heart's daughter, Annie Crows Heart Eagle. Begins at pg 113 of original text. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name.
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-07; 12-06; 1.0 .mp3; 01:21:28; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    The autobiographical text was collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Crows Heart, a Mandan, in 1947. The recording consists of the English version of the text being read in short chunks by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by free translations into Mandan, then Hidatsa, by Crows Heart's daughter, Annie Crows Heart Eagle. Begins at page 123 of original text. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name.
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-07; 12-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:34:02; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    The autobiographical text was collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Crows Heart, a Mandan, in 1947. The recording consists of the English version of the text being read in short chunks by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by free translations into Mandan, then Hidatsa, by Crows Heart's daughter, Annie Crows Heart Eagle. Begins at page 130 of original text. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name.
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-07; 13-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:39:52; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    The autobiographical text was collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Crows Heart, a Mandan, in 1947. The recording consists of the English version of the text being read in short chunks by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by free translations into Mandan, then Hidatsa, by Crows Heart's daughter, Annie Crows Heart Eagle. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name.
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-07; 13-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:48; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
  - A short account by Annie Crows Heart Eagle about her people, 1969-07; 13-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:46; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--Biography; Hidatsa language; Indians of North America--North Dakota
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-07; 13-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:57:05; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-07; 13-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:27:40; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-07; 13-05; 1.0 .mp3; 01:35:55; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-07; 13-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:45; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-07; 13-07; 1.0 .mp3; 02:08:00; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-07; 13-08; 1.0 .mp3; 01:52:44; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    The autobiographical text was collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Crows Heart, a Mandan, in 1947. The recording consists of the English version of the text being read in short chunks by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by free translations into Mandan, then Hidatsa, by Crows Heart's daughter, Annie Crows Heart Eagle. Begins at page 165 of original text. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name.
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-07; 13-09; 1.0 .mp3; 01:45:09; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    The autobiographical text was collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Crows Heart, a Mandan, in 1947. The recording consists of the English version of the text being read in short chunks by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by free translations into Mandan, then Hidatsa, by Crows Heart's daughter, Annie Crows Heart Eagle. Begins at page 171 of original text. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name.
    Autobiography; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--History; Mandan Indians--Biography; Mandan Indians--History; Mandan Indians--Social life and customs
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-07; 13-10; 1.0 .mp3; 01:07:52; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-08-01; 14-01; 1.0 .mp3; 02:17:07; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    The autobiographical text was collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Crows Heart, a Mandan, in 1947. The recording consists of the English version of the text being read in short chunks by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by free translations into Mandan, then Hidatsa, by Crows Heart's daughter, Annie Crows Heart Eagle. Begins at page 205 of original text. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name.
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-08-01; 14-02; 1.0 .mp3; 02:21:34; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    The autobiographical text was collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Crows Heart, a Mandan, in 1947. The recording consists of the English version of the text being read in short chunks by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by free translations into Mandan, then Hidatsa, by Crows Heart's daughter, Annie Crows Heart Eagle. Begins at pg 215 of original text. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name.
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-08-01; 14-03; 1.0 .mp3; 01:18:00; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
  - Personal narrative in Hidatsa, 1969-08-01; 14-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:27; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-08-01; 14-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:51:41; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-08; 14-06; 1.0 .mp3; 01:14:05; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    The autobiographical text was collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Crows Heart, a Mandan, in 1947. The recording consists of the English version of the text being read in short chunks by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by free translations into Mandan, then Hidatsa, by Crows Heart's daughter, Annie Crows Heart Eagle. Begins at page 232 of original text. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name.
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-08-05; 15-01; 1.0 .mp3; 02:04:39; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    The autobiographical text was collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Crows Heart, a Mandan, in 1947. The recording consists of the English version of the text being read in short chunks by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by free translations into Mandan, then Hidatsa, by Crows Heart's daughter, Annie Crows Heart Eagle. Begins at page 240 of original text. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name.
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-08-05; 15-02; 1.0 .mp3; 01:51:00; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-08-05; 15-03; 1.0 .mp3; 02:07:27; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    Text covers the purchase of horse medicine ceremonies. The autobiographical text was collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Crows Heart, a Mandan, in 1947. The recording consists of the English version of the text being read in short chunks by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by free translations into Mandan, then Hidatsa, by Crows Heart's daughter, Annie Crows Heart Eagle. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name.
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969-08-05; 15-04; 1.0 .mp3; 01:55:59; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
  - Crows Heart's first Eagle trapping (English-Hidatsa), 1969-08; 16-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:59:07; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    The autobiographical text was collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Crows Heart, a Mandan, in June of 1929. The recording consists of the English version of the text being read in short chunks by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by free translations into Hidatsa by Crows Heart's daughter, Annie Crows Heart Eagle. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name.
  - Crows Heart's first Eagle trapping (English-Mandan), 1969-08; 16-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:51:25; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart
    The autobiographical text was collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Crows Heart, a Mandan, in June of 1929. The recording consists of the English version of the text being read in short chunks by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by free translations into Hidatsa by Crows Heart's daughter, Annie Crows Heart Eagle.
  - White Calf's Mandan Origin Myth [1 of 2], 1969; 16-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:46:26; Bowers, Alfred W.; Otter Sage, Mrs.; White Calf, Frank
    Collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Frank White Calf in June 1929. Program cut-off before completion of program. Original master tape later re-recorded [APSdigrec_0776]. Later re-recording includes the entire program, but is of poorer quality.
    Anthropological linguistics; Autobiography; Creation--Mythology; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Indians of North America--North Dakota--History; Mandan Indians--Folklore
  - White Calf's Mandan Origin Myth [2 of 2], 1969; 16-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:48:50; Bowers, Alfred W.; Otter Sage, Mrs.; White Calf, Frank
    Collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Frank White Calf in June 1929. The Mandan speech is nearly inaudible up until about 4:40.
  - Crows Heart Autobiography, 1969; 16-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:09; Bowers, Alfred W.; Eagle, Annie Crows Heart; Otter Sage, Mrs.
    The autobiographical text was collected by Alfred W. Bowers from Crows Heart, a Mandan, in 1947. The recording consists of the English version of the text being read in short chunks by Alfred W. Bowers, followed by free translations into Mandan, then Hidatsa, by Crows Heart's daughter, Annie Crows Heart Eagle. Begins at page 50 of original text. The Hidatsa language is identified as such in the recording's accompanying documentation, but on the recording itself it is referred to by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name.
  - White Calf's Mandan Origin Myth [1 of 2], 1969; 16-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:59:12; Bowers, Alfred W.; Otter Sage, Mrs.; White Calf, Frank